A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H FA317
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Friends and Relations
  - Friends and Relations - Schweikert, Charles, 1935-1960 (Box 109, Folder 825)
    Reverend Doctor. North Baptist Church, Pastor. Trinity Baptist Church, Brooklyn. Personal gifts. An old friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. of Armitage Chapel days.
    108Sc
  - Friends and Relations - Seaver, Mrs. Francis, 1914-1919 (Box 110, Folder 826)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift. Seeking employment.
    108Se
  - Friends and Relations - Seldner, Harry L., 1912-1918 (Box 110, Folder 827)
    Chauffeur for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Accident. Financial help.
  - Friends and Relations - Sewall, Mrs. Charles, 1905-1937 (Box 110, Folder 828)
    Wife of Presbyterian minister in Rye, New York. Close friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in his youth; friendship through the years. Death.
    108Se4
  - Friends and Relations - Scott, Albert L., 1934-1946 (Box 110, Folder 829)
    President, Lockwood Greene Engineers, Incorporated. Led Missionary and liquor studies for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Foreign Mission Survey. Former President of Rockefeller Center, Incorporated. Riverside Church - President of the Board of Trustees.
    108Sc1
  - Friends and Relations - Sims, Mr. and Mrs. H. D., 1911-1957 (Box 110, Folder 830)
    Mr. Sims married Miss Rudd - her father George Rudd was John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s uncle's brother. Mr. Sims served in a secretarial capacity with John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. He went into Chandler and Rudd in Cleveland with his father-in-law. Financial aid to Chandler and Rudd. Personal gifts to Mr. and Mrs. Sims. Death of Mr. Sims.
    108Si5
  - Friends and Relations - Sked, Caroline, 1905-1937 (Box 110, Folder 831)
    For 50 years public school educator in Cleveland. Treasurer of Baptist Home. Active worker in the Euclid Avenue Baptist Church. Personal friend of Laura Spelman Rockefeller - established Trust Fund for Miss Sked. Death.
    108Sk1
  - Friends and Relations - Sleicher, John A., 1914-1921 (Box 110, Folder 832)
    Editor of Leslie's Weekly, newspaper. President of Leslie-Judge Company of New York, publishing. Served on Civil Service Commission of New York State. Matters of public concern that might interest John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Published some articles on John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his activities. Death.
    108Sl1
  - Friends and Relations - Sly, Roy C., 1934-1939 (Box 110, Folder 833)
    Male nurse; was in the employ of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; in need of employment after his dismissal.
    108Sl9
  - Friends and Relations - Smith, Alice C., 1922-1939 (Box 110, Folder 834)
    Worked for many years in Probation Bureau of City Magistrate's Court, New York City. Asking financial assistance.
    108Sm5
  - Friends and Relations - Smith, Mr. and Mrs. Brockholst, 1949-1959 (Box 111, Folder 835)
    Very close friends of Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Large amounts of financial aid for Mrs. Smith's illness. Death.
    108Sm
  - Friends and Relations - Smith, Mr. and Mrs. Brockholst, 1955 (Box 111, Folder 0835A)
  - Friends and Relations - Smith, Mr. and Mrs. Brockholst - Mrs. Palmer C. Putnam, 1949-1960 (Box 111, Folder 836)
    Mr. and Mrs. Smith's daughter, Helen. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gifts to Mrs. Putnam to help her through her illness.
  - Friends and Relations - Spelman, Frank J. and Lila, 1905-1940 (Box 111, Folder 837)
    Frank Spelman was the youngest brother of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s grandfather Spelman. Jennie and Lilla Spelman were Frank's daughters. Matters regarding Lucy Spelman's will in regard to these parties. Financial aid to all three persons.
    108Sp31
  - Friends and Relations - Stanton, Nicholas, 1906-1950 (Box 111, Folder 838)
    Worked for John D. Rockefeller, Sr. for over 25 years - mostly as caretaker of city residence; resigned his position after John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s death.
    108St1
  - Friends and Relations - Stark, Abraham I., 1926-1941 (Box 111, Folder 839)
    An attorney specializing in real estate; real estate propositions. Friendship of sons at Lincoln and Dartmouth. Helped him in obtaining office space for his firm; personal loans; suggestions to refrain from further assistance.
    108St11
  - Friends and Relations - Steele, John M., 1915-1929 (Box 111, Folder 840)
    Denver newspaperman - articles on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; personal loans - unable to repay. Various jobs.
    108St2
  - Friends and Relations - Stelzle, Charles, 1913-1934 (Box 111, Folder 841)
    Interpreter of International, Industrial, Social and Religious problems. Free-lance writer; Lecturer. Job applicant. Business proposition. Personal loan.
    108St3
  - Friends and Relations - Staley, F. S., 1926-1945 (Box 111, Folder 842)
    Vice-President and director of Normandy Realty Corporation, the Deckins Corporation and Van Tassel Garage Company. Acted for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on a number of personal matters.
    108St4
  - Friends and Relations - Stockmans, H. F., 1933-1935 (Box 112, Folder 843)
    Supplying plants.
    108.1S4
  - Friends and Relations - Stokes, P., 1916-1924 (Box 112, Folder 844)
    President of the Phelps-Stokes Fund. Worked on General Education Board with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Work on African Educational Commission.
    108St6
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Dr. John, 1911-1960 (Box 112, Folder 845)
    John and Nadine Strong - very close friends of Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Various experiences, travel, etc.
    108St8
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Dr. John, 1951 (Box 112, Folder 0845A)
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Charles and Bessie, 1886-1911 (Box 112, Folder 846)
    Charles Strong and Dr. John Strong were brothers. Financial gifts. Charles' professorship. Charles as administrator of his wife Bessie's estate. Bessie daughter of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
  - Friends and Relations - Estate of Bessie Rockefeller Strong, 1906-1933; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 113, Folder 847)
  - Friends and Relations - Estate of Bessie Rockefeller Strong, 1906-1933; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 113, Folder 848)
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Margaret, 1952-1961; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 113, Folder 849)
    Daughter of Bessie Rockefeller Strong. Married George de Cuevas. Financial affairs, family gifts.
    108St81
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Margaret, 1942-1951; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 113, Folder 0849A)
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Margaret, 1934-1941; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 113, Folder 850)
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Margaret, 1927-1933; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 113, Folder 0850A)
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Margaret, 1905-1926; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 113, Folder 0850B)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong, 1933-1937; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 114, Folder 851)
    Finances, debts.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong, 1930-1933; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 114, Folder 0851A)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong, 1931-1934; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 114, Folder 852)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong, 1934-1947; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 114, Folder 853)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong, 1933; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 114, Folder 854)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Staley's Reports, 1930-1933 (Box 115, Folder 855)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Statements of Indebtedness, 1931-1932 (Box 115, Folder 856)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Income Tax, 1930-1942 (Box 115, Folder 857)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Income Tax, 1919-1945 (Box 115, Folder 858)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Business Matters, 1930-1933 (Box 115, Folder 859)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. loans to M. Strong.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Domicile, 1930-1931 (Box 115, Folder 860)
    Choice of legal residence.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Gift of Standard Oil Stock, 1919-1928 (Box 115, Folder 861)
    Gift of 12,000 shares.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Dr. Howe, 1931-1933 (Box 115, Folder 862)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid M. Strong's doctor bills.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Interest Charge, 1925-1932 (Box 115, Folder 863)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. charges on loans to M. Strong.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - May Lawrenson, 1926-1930 (Box 115, Folder 864)
    Gifts to former governess.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Office Account, 1924-1930 (Box 115, Folder 865)
    Account with John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Paris House, 1931-1936 (Box 115, Folder 0865A)
    Cost of repairs.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Will, 1930 (Box 115, Folder 866)
    Additional provision.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Trust, 1930-1938 (Box 115, Folder 0866A)
    Set up by John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; revoked by M. Strong.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Correspondence, 1930-1937 (Box 116, Folder 867)
    Financial problems.
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Contractors Settlement, St. Germain, 1933-1936 (Box 116, Folder 868)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Bills Paid, 1935-1937 (Box 116, Folder 869)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Statements, 1934-1936 (Box 116, Folder 870)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Foreign Taxes, 1934-1935 (Box 116, Folder 871)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - One Beekman Place, 1931-1934; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 116, Folder 872)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - One Beekman Place, 1930; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 116, Folder 0872A)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Strong Cottage, 1932-1944 (Box 116, Folder 873)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Statements, 1934-1937 (Box 117, Folder 874)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Trust Fund, 1930-1931 (Box 117, Folder 875)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Mrs. Margaret Strong - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Estate, 1916-1927 (Box 117, Folder 876)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, John, 1931-1958; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 117, Folder 877)
    Restricted material
    108St811
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, John, 1945-1958; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 117, Folder 0877A)
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Bessie (Mrs. Faure, Mrs. Carmichael), 1942-1961 (Box 117, Folder 878)
    108St812
  - Friends and Relations - de Cuevas, Bessie (Mrs. Faure, Mrs. Carmichael), 1952-1957 (Box 117, Folder 878A)
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Charles A., 1914-1958; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 117, Folder 879)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s brother-in-law; correspondence from Switzerland. Death. Letters from Marta Boschen.
    108St82
  - Friends and Relations - Strong, Charles A., 1914-1958; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 117, Folder 0879A)
  - Friends and Relations - Stuart, Sir Campbell, 1924-1953 (Box 117, Folder 880)
    Managing director of London "Times," friend of MacKenzie King.
    108St9
  - Friends and Relations - Teagle, Walter C., 1930-1960 (Box 118, Folder 881)
    President of Standard Oil of New Jersey sent John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts of fish and game.
    108T1
  - Friends and Relations - Talbot, Arnold, 1910-1957 (Box 118, Folder 882)
    Providence friend of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, did tapestry work. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased scarfs and sweaters, gave aid during illness.
  - Friends and Relations - Toole, Rev. V. J., 1918-1924 (Box 118, Folder 0882A)
    Met John D. Rockefeller, Jr. during War Bond parade; war-time experiences; asked for aid, got one small anonymous gift.
    108T5
  - Friends and Relations - Towne, Charles W., 1917-1960; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 118, Folder 883)
    Brown classmate, author, did Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) work; gifts from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    108T6
  - Friends and Relations - Towne, Charles W., 1917-1960; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 118, Folder 0883A)
  - Friends and Relations - Trevor, John B., 1927-1956 (Box 118, Folder 884)
    Chairman of Citizens Committee on Immigration Legislation, American Coalition of Patriotic Societies. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution to immigration restriction.
    108T7
  - Friends and Relations - Tucker, William and Sarah, 1929-1940 (Box 118, Folder 885)
    Sold Rockefeller property to John D. Rockefeller, Sr. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. carried an account for them on his books.
    108T8
  - Friends and Relations - Tucker, Garrett, 1922-1935 (Box 118, Folder 886)
    Laborer for United States customs collapsed in John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s house; widow's effects to assure government compensations.
  - Friends and Relations - Touffier, Dr. Thomas, 1922-1925 (Box 119, Folder 887)
    French M.D. active in China met John D. Rockefeller, Jr. there; donation to testimonial for him.
    108T83
  - Friends and Relations - Tuttle, Morton C., 1922-1925 (Box 119, Folder 888)
    Boston engineer interested in housing problems; Charles O. Heydt interest.
    108T84
  - Friends and Relations - Tyler, Charles H., 1921-1952 (Box 119, Folder 889)
    Loans to builder who did work for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    108T9
  - Friends and Relations - Upshaw, William D., 1918-1959; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 119, Folder 890)
    Religious lecturer and evangelist had attended John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Bible class; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to his family.
    108U5
  - Friends and Relations - Upshaw, William D., 1928-1959; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 119, Folder 891)
  - Friends and Relations - Upshaw, William D., 1928-1959; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 119, Folder 0891A)
  - Friends and Relations - Upshaw, William D., 1928-1959; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 119, Folder 0891B)
  - Friends and Relations - Urguhart, B. C. and L. C., 1908-1934 (Box 120, Folder 892)
    Loan to John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s Cleveland friend; interest payment on loan.
    108U61
  - Friends and Relations - Wakefield, Anna M., 1910-1918 (Box 120, Folder 893)
    Small gifts.
    108W1
  - Friends and Relations - Watson, Dr. C. R., 1919-1944 (Box 120, Folder 894)
    International worker in missionary field wrote copiously - "Re-thinking Missions," reports from Cairo during war; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. very interested in him.
  - Friends and Relations - Webb, F. E., 1934-1949 (Box 120, Folder 895)
    Gifts to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. friends who lived in Italy for long periods; wartime experiences.
    108W11
  - Friends and Relations - Wehrle, C. S., 1917-1947 (Box 120, Folder 896)
    Mrs. Wehrle directed Cleveland Sunday School orchestra in which John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his sisters played.
    108W15
  - Friends and Relations - Welborn, J. F., 1915-1945 (Box 120, Folder 897)
    President of Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I); wife's death; financial affairs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts; need for money to send son through college. Death.
    108W2
  - Friends and Relations - Wells, E. H., 1911-1916 (Box 120, Folder 898)
    Harvard friend of J. P. Greene worked in office for six months, quit.
    108W3
  - Friends and Relations - White, Rev. C. E., 1922-1935 (Box 120, Folder 899)
    Brown classmate appealed for aid in personal troubles; small sums sent via Willard S. Richardson.
  - Friends and Relations - White, John P., 1928-1943; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 121, Folder 900)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. business loans to Cleveland friend during depression to keep his finance company going. Small gifts; visits to Florida by Mr. and Mrs. White.
    108W4
  - Friends and Relations - White, John P., 1928-1943; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 121, Folder 0900A)
  - Friends and Relations - Whitman, Charles S., 1913-1925 (Box 121, Folder 901)
    Governor of New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to political campaigns.
    108W41
  - Friends and Relations - Whiting, Mrs. H. H., 1910-1917 (Box 121, Folder 902)
    Tutor for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s children; fees and expenses.
    108W42
  - Friends and Relations - Wheeler, Harry, 1913-1914 (Box 121, Folder 903)
    Chicago banker John D. Rockefeller, Jr. considered employing.
    108W43
  - Friends and Relations - Weitzel, E. H., 1927-1951; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 121, Folder 904)
    General manager CF&I; resolution of strike; friendship with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Retirement; his family; gifts.
    108W5
  - Friends and Relations - Weitzel, E. H., 1927-1951; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 121, Folder 0904A)
  - Friends and Relations - Witter, William, 1912-1921 (Box 121, Folder 905)
    Baptist missionary who served in India.
    108W51
  - Friends and Relations - Woelfkin, Rev. Cornelius, 1910-1933; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 122, Folder 906)
    Minister of Fifth Avenue Baptist Church.
    108W7
  - Friends and Relations - Woelfkin, Rev. Cornelius, 1910-1933; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 122, Folder 0906A)
  - Friends and Relations - Woodmansee, Franz, 1916-1933 (Box 122, Folder 907)
    Pianist, taught Abby Aldrich Rockefeller; several small gifts from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    108W71
  - Friends and Relations - Wood, Charles H., 1912-1941 (Box 122, Folder 908)
    Financial aid to baggage master at Grand Central Station.
    108W8
  - Friends and Relations - Woods, Arthur, 1922-1953 (Box 122, Folder 909)
    Special projects for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; expenses; call from President Hoover for Washington work. Many cryptic comments. Death; distribution of his files.
    108W9
  - Friends and Relations - Walker, Mrs. Morton Blaine, 1943-1959 (Box 122, Folder 910)
    Her letters ignored by office.
    108W
  - Friends and Relations - Walker, Mrs. Morton Blaine, 1943-1959 (Box 122, Folder 0910A)
  - Friends and Relations - Yordi, John H., 1918-1938 (Box 123, Folder 911)
    New York office handled his investments; nurse for John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
    108Y6
  - Friends and Relations - Zilberman, Mrs. B. N., 1915-1959 (Box 123, Folder 912)
    Socialist, woman suffragette met John D. Rockefeller, Jr., asked his cooperation, sent steady stream of comment to office; no acknowledgement.
    108Z
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Lists, 1912-1956 (Box 123, Folder 913)
    Rockefeller interest in marriages, deaths, retirements.
    108.1
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Lists, 1918-1959 (Box 123, Folder 914)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Lists, 1953-1956 (Box 123, Folder 0914A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Lakewood, 1918-1961 (Box 123, Folder 915)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Lakewood, 1948-1961 (Box 123, Folder 0915A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees, 1918-1956 (Box 123, Folder 916)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees, 1952 (Box 123, Folder 0916A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Webb, 1940-1959 (Box 124, Folder 917)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Richardson, 1941-1959 (Box 124, Folder 918)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Richardson, 1950 (Box 124, Folder 918A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees, 1932-1961 (Box 124, Folder 919)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees, 1959-1961 (Box 124, Folder 0919A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Heydt, 1933-1959 (Box 124, Folder 920)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Warfield/Gumbel, 1961-1965 (Box 124, Folder 921)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Warfield/Gumbel, 1962-1965 (Box 124, Folder 0921A)
    Restricted from scholarly access - confidential material
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Ambrose, 1937-1965 (Box 124, Folder 922)
    108.11
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Chipman, LeRoy, 1949-1954 (Box 124, Folder 922A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Margot/Rogers/Lakewood, 1916-1951 (Box 124, Folder 923)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Cutler, 1906-1952 (Box 125, Folder 924)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Cutler, 1952 (Box 125, Folder 924A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Madison, 1909-1960 (Box 125, Folder 925)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Madison, 1941-1955 (Box 125, Folder 0925A)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Berg/Turnbull/Scholl, 1937-1950 (Box 125, Folder 926)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Robert W. Gumbel give small gifts to Hilda Berg, John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s retired laundress.
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Perschok, 1939-1943 (Box 125, Folder 927)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Perschok, 1929-1949 (Box 125, Folder 928)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees - Baisden/Scholl, 1937-1947 (Box 125, Folder 929)
  - Friends and Relations - Office Employees, 1922-1942 (Box 125, Folder 930)
  - Friends and Relations - Archie Fawkes, 1937-1940 (Box 125, Folder 931)
    Shepherd at Lakewood, refused to vacate house; evicted.
  - Friends and Relations - Chauffeurs and Coachmen, 1902-1960 (Box 126, Folder 932)
    Rates of pay, vacations, retirement.
  - Friends and Relations - Chauffeurs and Coachmen, 1922-1925 (Box 126, Folder 933)
  - Friends and Relations - Chauffeurs and Coachmen - Stapleton/Phillips, 1911-1938 (Box 126, Folder 934)
  - Friends and Relations - Concannon, John and Mrs., 1922-1933; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 126, Folder 935)
    Chauffeur; illness and death; employment of wife.
  - Friends and Relations - Concannon, John and Mrs., 1940-1953; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 126, Folder 936)
  - Friends and Relations - Concannon, Timothy, 1915-1956 (Box 126, Folder 937)
    Wages; housing; retirement. Death; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. assistance to widow.
  - Friends and Relations - Frasca, Vincent, 1937-1952 (Box 126, Folder 938)
    Personal chauffeur of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. dismissed by Alta Prentice; financial aid.
  - Friends and Relations - Carmody, James, 1935-1940 (Box 126, Folder 939)
    Groom at Pocantico Hills recommended by Bertram Cutler.
  - Friends and Relations - Morrissey, Michael, 1932-1947 (Box 127, Folder 940)
    Florida butler, retired; pension from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Friends and Relations - Employees - Chauffeurs, 1915-1961; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 127, Folder 941)
  - Friends and Relations - Employees - Chauffeurs, 1942; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 127, Folder 941A)
  - Friends and Relations - Employees - Chauffeurs, 1930-1960; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 127, Folder 942)
  - Friends and Relations - Employees - Chauffeurs, 1942; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 127, Folder 942A)
  - Friends and Relations - Bloomingdales, 1938-1954 (Box 127, Folder 0942B)
    Account settlements; credit cards.
  - Friends and Relations - Curtis and Belknap, 1938-1949 (Box 127, Folder 943)
    Approval of bills by Thomas M. Debevoise; membership of firm.
    108.1C9
  - Friends and Relations - E. P. Dutton and Company, 1915-1947 (Box 127, Folder 944)
    Declinations to invest in publishing business; comments on books; free copies. Purchases.
    108.1D
  - Friends and Relations - Douglas, Gibbons, & Company, 1936-1957 (Box 127, Folder 0944A)
    Managed Rockefeller property.
    108.1D5
  - Friends and Relations - Florists, 1915-1952 (Box 127, Folder 945)
    Purchase of flowers; gifts of flowers to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. by Denver florist.
    108.1F
  - Friends and Relations - Fahnestock & Company, 1934-1956 (Box 127, Folder 946)
    Requests for brokerage by Rockefeller Center tenant; a little business from Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    108.1F1
  - Friends and Relations - Gerlach, Reebach, & Fuller, 1936 (Box 127, Folder 0946A)
    108.1G3